A Finding Aid to the Dorothy Dehner Papers, 1920-1987 (bulk 1951-1987), in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Correspondence, 1927-1987; Series 2; Archival Resource Key; 2.2 Linear feet
  - Lowe, Ira, 1965-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 96)
    Documents Dehner's attempts to retrieve a sculpture David Smith made for her.
  - M, General, 1955-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 97)
  - Matulka, Mrs. Jan, 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 98)
    Relates to Jan Matulka's estate
  - Mann, Ferdinand, circa 1950s-circa 1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 99)
  - Marcus, Stanley, circa 1975-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 100)
  - Marion Locks Gallery, 1975-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Marter, Joan (Rutgers University), circa 1979-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Marter later became head of Dehner Foundation
  - McCampbell, Kay, circa 1967-circa 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - McCandless, Judith, 1973-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - McClintic, Miranda, circa 1978-circa 1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - McClintic, Miranda, 1976-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Dehner assisted McClintic on a catalog of David Smith's work for the Hirshhorn Museum
  - Members' Gallery, Albright-Knox Art Gallery, 1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Munson-Williams-Proctor Institute, 1960-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Museum of Art, Carnegie Institute, 1982-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Museum of Fine Arts, Boston, 1959-1966, 1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Museum of Modern Art, 1956-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Museum of Modern Art, 1968-1971, 1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - N, General, 1960-1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Nash, Mary, 1975-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - National Association of Women Artists, 1966-1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - National Collection of Fine Arts, Smithsonian Institution/National Museum of American Art, 1978-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Nevelson, Louise, 1960s-1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - North Jersey Cultural Council, 1970-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - O, General, 1965-1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - P, General, 1957-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Paine, Stephen, 1969-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Parsons School of Design (New York WPA Artists Exhibition), 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Pease, Marion, circa 1948-circa 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Peterson, Robert, 1971-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Philadelphia Art Alliance, 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Phillips Collection, 1985-1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Pond, Jean Smith, 1965-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 27)
    Pond was David Smith's second wife
  - Pond, Jean Smith, 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Prasse, Leona, 1967-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - R, General, 1953-1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Raymond Burr Galleries, 1963-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Robinson, Helen, 1975, 1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Rubenstein, Charlotte, 1980-1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Rutgers University, 1982-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Ruth White Gallery, 1960-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - S, General, 1946-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Sadwith, Lucille, 1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 37)
    Includes transcript of an interview Sadwith conducted with Dehner
  - Sculptors Guild, Inc., 1967-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Shaeffer, Louis, 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Skidmore College, circa 1960s-circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Skidmore College, 1948-1949, 1960-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Skidmore College, 1970-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Skidmore College, 1978-1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Smith, Candida, circa 1976-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Smith, Catherine, circa 1960s-circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 45)
    Catherine Smith was David Smith's sister
  - Smith, Catherine, 1950-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Smith, Catherine, 1967-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Smith, Catherine, 1969-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Smith, Catherine, 1972-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 49)
    Includes letter relating to Clement Greenberg's handling of David Smith's estate.
  - Smith, David, 1927-1928; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 50)
    Letters are primarily typed transcripts
  - Smith, David, 1944-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Smith, David, 1951-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Smith, Golda, circa 1960s-circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Smith, Golda, 1950, 1964-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Smith, Rebecca, circa 1974, 1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Smith, Sarah Kathryn, 1976-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Stamford Museum and Nature Center, 1984-1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - State University College at Potsdam, 1971-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Stern, H. Peter, 1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Storm King Art Center, circa 1963-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Storm King Art Center, 1978-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Studio Museum in Harlem, 1986-1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Syracuse University, 1964-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - T, General, circa 1948-circa 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Tamarind Lithography Workshop, circa 1970-circa 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 65)
    Includes preparatory sketches for artwork
  - Tamarind Lithography Workshop, 1963-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Thayer, William, 1980-1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Thernstrom, Abigail, Melanie and Stephen, circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Traxel, David, 1976-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Tully, Judd, 1981-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Twining Gallery, 1984-1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - U, General, 1964-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - University Art Museum, State University of New York at Albany, circa 1974-circa 1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - University of Cincinnati, 1986-1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 74)
    Documents exhibition of the National Sculpture Conference "Works by Women"
  - University of New Mexico, 1974-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - V, General, 1966-1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Various, Condolence Letters, 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Various, Family, 1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Various, Great Southwest Industrial Park (Atlanta, GA), 1967-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 79)
    Relates to Dehner's commission for this unrealized project.
  - Various, Jan Matulka Painting, 1968-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 80)
    Fund of artist contributions raised to place a painting by Matulka in a New York museum.
  - Various, Painted Surfaces of David Smith Sculptures, 1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 81)
    Includes Catherine Smith's letter to Clement Greenberg referenced in Box 2, Folder 49
  - Various, Round Robin Letter, 1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - Various, Traveling Exhibition, Dorothy Dehner: Watercolors and Drawings (1953-1954), 1951-1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - Various, Traveling Exhibition, Dorothy Dehner: Watercolors and Drawings (1953-1954), Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - W, General, 1944-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - White, Tracy, circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - Whitney Museum of American Art, 1961-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 87)
  - Wichita Art Museum, 1984-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 88)
  - Wichita State University, 1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Willard Gallery, circa 1946-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Gallery represented Dehner in the 1950s-1970s
  - Willard, Marian, 1967-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - William Pall Gallery, 1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Women's Caucus for Art, 1982-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Women's Interart Center, 1973-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Xceron, John and Marie, circa 1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Yaddo, 1968-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Zimmerli Art Museum, Rutgers University, 1983-1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 9)
    Documents exhibition Dorothy Dehner and David Smith: Their Decade of Search and Fulfillment
  - First Names Only, circa 1949-1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Unidentified/Illegible Names, circa 1940s-circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Interviews, 1963-1981; Series 3; Archival Resource Key; 0.5 Linear feet
  Series consists of sound recordings of three interviews with Dehner by Herman Cherry, Judith McCandless, and ---- Rapp, and an interview conducted for a documentary on David Smith. Also found here is a list of people who interviewed Dehner, and the transcript of an interview with K--- Osis.
  Researchers interested in accessing audiovisual recordings in this collection must use access copies. Contact References Services for more information.
  - List of Dehner Interviewers, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Sound Recording of Interview by Herman Cherry, 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Item 1)
  - Sound Recording of Interview by Herman Cherry, Duplicate, 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Item 2)
  - Sound Recording of Interview by Herman Cherry, Duplicate, 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Item 3)
  - Sound Recording of Interview by Judith McCandless, 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Item 4)
  - Sound Recording of Interview by Judith McCandless, 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Item 5)
  - Sound Recording of Interview by Judith McCandless, 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Item 6)
  - Sound Recording of Interview by Judith McCandless, Duplicate, 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Item 7)
  - Sound Recording of Interview by Judith McCandless, Duplicate, 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Item 8)
  - Sound Recording of Interview by Judith McCandless, Duplicate, 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Item 9)
  - Sound Recording of Interview by ? Rapp, Duplicate, 1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Item 10)
  - Sound Recording of Interview by ? Rapp, Duplicate, 1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Item 11)
  - Sound Recording of Interview by ? Rapp, Duplicate, 1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Item 12)
  - Sounding Recording of Interview for David Smith Documentary, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Item 13)
  - Sounding Recording of Interview for David Smith Documentary, Duplicate, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Item 14)
  - Sounding Recording of Interview for David Smith Documentary, Duplicate, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Item 15)
  - Transcript of Interview with K? Osis, 1963 May 1; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Transcript of Interview with K? Osis, 1963 May 16; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Writings, 1920-1987; Series 4; Archival Resource Key; 0.25 Linear feet
  Series consists of the writings by Dorothy Dehner, including articles, poems, lectures and speeches, and other pieces. Writings document some of the influences on Dehner's art, some of her ideas about art in general and certain works in particular, and some of her other creative and more scholarly endeavors. Writings by others include instances of the scholarly interpretation of her work by others.
  The bulk of this series has been digitized. Duplicates copies of writings with no annotations have not been digitized.
  - Writings by Dorothy Dehner, 1920-1977; 4.1; Archival Resource Key
    Series includes various drafts, proofs, and reprints relating to Dehner's essay on John Graham, which was initially written as a foreword to Graham's Systems and Dialectics of Art re-issued by Johns Hopkins Press in 1971, but was first published as an article in the art journal, Leonardo in 1968; note that related material can be found in Series 2: Correspondence. Also found is material related to Dehner's essay on David Smith's work, "Medals for Dishonor," which was published as an article in Art Journal in 1977. Records consist of correspondence (mostly copies), including a copy of a David Smith letter with his suggested text to accompany the work, printed material, and drafts of Dehner's article. A draft of a memoir of Dehner's first meeting with Smith written for Art in America can also be found here.
    Dehner's other writings on art include notes and copies of various speeches and lectures given at the Artists Club, the Cummer Gallery of Art, and elsewhere; various statements on art, including remarks on the Menorah, a plan of work, and a short piece on the series of paintings, Life on the Farm; and contributions to catalogs for others, including ones for Joel Levy and Joan Paul. Dehner's poems include one she wrote in high school, manuscripts of two that were published in the journal, Tracks, and poems she wrote for her stepdaughter and granddaughter. Other writings include notes taken during a stay in the hospital in 1933, and later reflective and memoir pieces such as were written for her granddaughter, upon the death of Marian Willard, and on other occasions.
    Student work includes papers dating from Dehner's time at Skidmore College in 1951-1952, including an essay on eighteen artists and the Metropolitan Art Museum, and notes from a class she took on Oriental Cultures.
    - "A Response to the Work of Joan Paul", undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Artist Statements, circa 1956-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Biographical Writings, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - "David Smith: First Meeting", circa 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 18)
      Draft for Art in America
    - "For Melanie", undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Joel Levy Catalog Foreword Draft, 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - "John Graham: A Memoir" Draft, circa 1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - "John Graham: A Memoir" Proof, 1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - "John Graham: A Memoir" Reprint in Leonardo, 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - John Graham, Notes on?, circa 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - John Graham's System and Dialectics of Art, Foreword Draft, 1966-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - John Graham's System and Dialectics of Art, Foreword Draft, 1966-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - John Graham's System and Dialectics of Art, Foreword Proof, 1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Lectures and Speeches, College Art Association Meeting Speech Notes, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Lectures and Speeches, Cummer Art Gallery Lecture, circa 1966-circa 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Lectures and Speeches, Parsons School of Design Lecture Notes, 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Lectures and Speeches, Sculpture Forum at the Artists Club Speech, circa 1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - "Medals for Dishonor: The Fifteen Medallions of David Smith," Drafts, circa 1968-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - "Medals for Dishonor: The Fifteen Medallions of David Smith," Drafts, circa 1968-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - "Medals for Dishonor: The Fifteen Medallions of David Smith," Research Material, 1940, 1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Notebook, Hospital Notes, circa 1933; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Notes, Miscellaneous, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - "Of Death and Life", undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - "Plexiglass Relief for the Great Southwest Industrial Park" Reprint in Leonardo, 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Poems, 1920-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - "Remembering Marian" (Willard), 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Student Work, Essay "Survey of Eighteen Artists and [the Metropolitan Museum]", 1951-1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Student Work, Notes from Class on Oriental Culture, 1951-1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Student Work, Notes from Class on Oriental Culture, 1951-1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Writings by Others, 1953-1987; 4.2; Archival Resource Key
    Writings by others comprise manuscripts for essays on Dehner which appeared in catalogs accompanying exhibitions of her work at Rutgers University in 1984 ("Dorothy Dehner: Life and Work" by Judith McCandless) and Baruch College in 1991 ("Dorothy Dehner" by Joan Marter). Also found here are poems by Herman Cherry and a copy of a speech, "The Origins of Sculpture" given by David Smith in 1953.
    - Cherry, Herman, Poems, 1974-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Marter, Joan, "Dorothy Dehner", 1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - McCandless, Judith, "Dorothy Dehner: Life and Work", 1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - McCandless, Judith, "Dorothy Dehner: Life-Line in Sculpture", 1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Smith, David, Speech in Norman, Oklahoma, 1953 May 1; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Unknown, Footnotes to Article on Dorothy Dehner, circa 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 49)
- Business and Financial Records, 1940-1987; Series 5; Archival Resource Key; 0.25 Linear feet
  Series consists of papers relating to various art and personal business matters and to certain financial matters. Some material is organized loosely into gallery and organization files, which may contain records of consignments, loans, sales, and exhibitions including ones at the Philadelphia Art Alliance in 1962, Editions Alecto, Ltd. in 1964, and the Parsons-Dreyfuss Gallery in 1979. The series also includes a file for Willard Gallery which represented Dehner from the mid-1950s to the 1970s, and a file related to the Committee for the American Participation in the Triennale.
  Material relating to more general art business consists of numerous handwritten and typed lists (of works, art sales, prices, exhibitions, art books donated to Skidmore College Library, etc.); visitor books for unidentified exhibitions in 1957, 1959, 1960, and 1963; shipping and delivery receipts; and handwritten documents authenticating certain David Smith works. Material relating to personal business and financial matters includes property and school tax records for Bolton's Landing; a receipt for payment by David Smith, presumably made to Dehner as part of their separation agreement; and an agreement by Dehner to sell certain sculptures by David Smith that she owned to Samuel Dorsky.
  The bulk of this series has been digitized. Mailing lists have not been digitized.
  - Agreement to Sell Sculptures by David Smith, 1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Exhibition Records, Miscellaneous, circa 1944-1967, 1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Galleries and Organizations, American Federation of Arts, 1960-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Galleries and Organizations, Associated American Artists, 1971-1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Galleries and Organizations, Committee for the American Participation in the Triennale, 1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Galleries and Organizations, Editions Alecto, Ltd., 1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Galleries and Organizations, Museum of Modern Art, 1952-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Galleries and Organizations, Parsons-Dreyfuss Gallery, 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Galleries and Organizations, Philadelphia Art Alliance, 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Galleries and Organizations, Willard Gallery, 1957-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Lists, Art Books Donated to Skidmore College Library, 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Lists, Art Sales, 1963, 1977-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Lists, Art Works at Home, circa 1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Lists, David Smith Paintings Owned by Dehner, 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Lists, Disposition of Certain Artworks, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Lists, Exhibitions and Photographs, circa 1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Lists, Mailing, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Lists, Miscellaneous, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Lists, Prices and Works Exhibited and Sold, 1950s-1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Property Tax Records, 1940-1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - Receipt, David Smith Paintings, 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 70)
    Includes authentication by Dorothy Dehner
  - Receipt, House Payment by David Smith, 1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Receipts, Shipping and Delivery, circa 1960s-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - Visitor Book, Exhibitions (1957, 1963), Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - Visitor Book, Exhibitions (1959, 1960), Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - Visitor Log, Exhibition (1970), Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 75)
- Printed Material, 1940-1987; Series 6; Archival Resource Key; 0.5 Linear feet
  Series consists of printed material collected and accumulated by Dehner, including exhibition catalogs, announcements, and invitations for her solo and group shows, clippings, art catalogs, programs, and miscellaneous printed material, pertaining to her own work, the work of David Smith, and, to a limited extent, the work of others. Clippings on Smith concern his death in 1965 and posthumous alterations to the painted surfaces of some of his outdoor sculptures (at the hands or through the negligence of Clement Greenberg, one of the executors of Smith's estate), which was a source of some controversy in the art world of the mid-1970s.
  This series has been selectively digitized. For publications, only covers and relevant pages relating to Dehner may be digitized.
  - Art Catalogs, 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - Book Excerpts on David Smith, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - Clippings, Dorothy Dehner, circa 1940s-circa 1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - Clippings, Dorothy Dehner, 1964-circa 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - Clippings, David Smith, circa 1959-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 80)